Hello.
The next thing we're going to do is set up the animations for our player character.
If we just right click and create a new folder and just call this animations.
And head inside it, then right click and go to Paper Z and go to animation source.
Just call this R Warrior animation source.
Just quick and open it up.
So this is part of the plugin that we installed.
This animation source, we're going to basically use this to store all the animations that we want associated
with our 2D player character.
Put aside Prasa and go new, then select new animation sequence.
Right click on this animation sequence and just pull this runner.
Then under animation data set the run flipbook.
Then click add new new animation sequence.
Cool.
This one.
It'll.
And let the idle flipbook.
We're going to add some more animations later.
But for now, these are all the animations that we need.
Click, save and close this.
Then right click and go People's ID and select the People's ID Animation Blueprint.
It's going to ask us what animation tools we want to use, just like the warrior animation source that
we just made and just call this a Warrior Z animation blueprint.
And then we'll click an open up.
If you are familiar with unreal engines, normal animation blueprints for 3D characters.
This is kind of similar for those for 2D characters.
If you're not, don't worry.
I'm going to explain everything I do as I go along.
So currently we're going to start in the event graph and they're going to be two nodes, event tech
and event on INT.
So this event on end will run as soon as the game starts.
So a bit on end, we're going to create a reference to our player VP.
In order to do this, just right click and forget owning.
Let's get opening act.
So this one, people did get opening act and this will be able to get a reference to the player character
that we're playing guess just track of here and a full course to play a BP and hook us into here Just
right click on this player, beep and convert it to a variable.
This will allow us to reference our character later on.
Next, I want you to head over to the animation graph.
Andrew Impey as paper BP.
Track of it and get velocity.
And I want you to strike a fair and full break.
To.
And of of the x and for not equal.
So if my character's velocity in the x axis is not equal to zero, we're going to make it so our player
character will play a certain animation to just drag up here and a full blend.
This one.
Select animations by Bull.
And hook up animation to here.
So if our characters velocity is not equal to zero, then we're going to play the running animation
if that means our player character is running.
So we just right click and play run.
And we're referencing the run that we made in this animation source.
And we can hook this up here.
And under post, we can just drag up here and play.
And we're going to go compile.
Then if we head over to our play app in order to make it, use this Warner Z animation blueprint to
select this animation component.
And here, under an instant class, set the Warrior Z animation blueprint and just go compile and we
can just close this and go play.
And if I move, my velocity is greater than zero and the x axis, my character will do that running
animation.
So with this, we have set up a running animation for our character.
If I just stand still, am I velocity is equal to zero, then I'll do my animation.
So nice with this.
We set up some basic animations for our player character.